<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Data Show Notebooks</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 12:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Working age population in G7 countries</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/working-age-population-in-G7-countries/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to OECD, the working age population corresponds to people aged 15 to 64. This indicator measures the share of the working-age population in the total population. What is the evolution of the working age population indicator in G7 countries over the years ?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-11-01:/working-age-population-in-G7-countries/</guid><category>Economics</category></item><item><title>Labour productivity in OECD countries</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/labour-productivity-in-OECD-countries/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to OECD, gross domestic product (GDP) is the standard measure of the value added created through the production of goods and services in a country during a certain period. GDP per hour worked measures the productivity of labor, and the efficiency with which labor input and other factors of production are used in the production process. The labor factor is the total number of hours worked by all the individuals involved in production. What is the evolution of labour productivity for G7 countries over the years ?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-10-31:/labour-productivity-in-OECD-countries/</guid><category>Economics</category></item><item><title>Hours worked in OECD countries</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/hours-worked-in-OECD-countries/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to OECD, the average number of annual hours worked corresponds to the total number of hours worked divided by the average number of people in employment, for a given annual period. What is the evolution of the average number of hours worked per week per employee in G7 countries over the years ?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-10-30:/hours-worked-in-OECD-countries/</guid><category>Economics</category></item><item><title>Who dominates the global smartphone market in 2020 ?</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/who-dominates-the-global-smartphone-market-in-2020/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While Samsung dominates year after year a saturated market and Apple signs a record fourth quarter of 2020, the war between Huawei and the United States continues. The Chinese telecommunications giant continues its inexorable rise despite restrictions and uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 12:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-10-17:/who-dominates-the-global-smartphone-market-in-2020/</guid><category>Economics</category></item><item><title>American Lawful Immigration 2018 : New LPRs by State of Residence</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/american-lawful-immigration-2018-new-lprs-by-state-of-residence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legal Permanent Residents (LPRs) are non-citizens who are lawfully authorized to live permanently within the United States. Let's explore data from the U.S. Department of Homeland Security to highlight the states in which people who received a green card in 2018 settled.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-10-13:/american-lawful-immigration-2018-new-lprs-by-state-of-residence/</guid><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>American Lawful Immigration 2018 : New LPRs by Country of Birth</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/american-lawful-immigration-2018-new-lprs-by-country-of-birth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legal Permanent Residents (LPRs) are non-citizens legally permitted to live permanently in the United States. Let’s explore the data from the U.S. Department of Homeland Security to highlight the regions and countries of birth of those people who received a green card in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 20:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-09-04:/american-lawful-immigration-2018-new-lprs-by-country-of-birth/</guid><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>World Press Freedom Index 2020</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/world-press-freedom-index-2020/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Press Freedom Index, yearly produced by Reporters Without Borders is a ranking of 180 countries which attempts to represent the degree of freedom that journalists, media, and netizens have in each country. The index is calculated on a scale from 0 to 100, the higher a country's score, the more worrying the press situation is. Using RSF data, we will visually represent this index of press freedom on maps.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-09-02:/world-press-freedom-index-2020/</guid><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Individuals using the Internet (% of population) from 1990 to 2017</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/individuals-using-internet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The digital and information revolution has dramatically changed the way the world communicates, learns, does business and treats disease. Indeed, the new information and communications technologies (ICTs) offer vast possibilities for advancement in all fields in all countries, from the most to the least developed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 22:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-05-04:/individuals-using-internet/</guid><category>Economics</category></item><item><title>World Bank Indicators - GDP per capita from 1960 to 2018</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/world-bank-indicators-gdp/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;GDP per capita is gross domestic product divided by midyear total population. GDP is the sum of gross value added by all resident producers in the economy plus any product taxes and minus any subsidies not included in the value of the products. GDP per capita is a good measurement of a country's standard of living, by describing how much citizens benefit from their country's economy. Small, rich countries and more developed industrial countries tend to have the highest per capita GDP. Data are in current U.S. dollars.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 18:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-05-02:/world-bank-indicators-gdp/</guid><category>Economics</category></item><item><title>Social Vulnerability Index 2018 - United States</title><link>https://notebooks.data-show.com/social-vulnerability-index-2018-united-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;CDC’s Social Vulnerability Index (SVI) is a tool to spatially identify and socially vulnerable populations. The SVI uses U.S. Census variables that reflect at-risk populations to identify and map vulnerable areas. Information on the location and relative concentration of different types of social vulnerabilities in small geographic areas, such as census tracts can help emergency managers locate and plan for the specific needs of their communities, before, during, and after a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Data Show</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 23:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:notebooks.data-show.com,2020-04-09:/social-vulnerability-index-2018-united-states/</guid><category>Health</category></item></channel></rss>